<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poll on RubyLearning Blog</title>
    <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/categories/poll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Poll on RubyLearning Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://rubylearning.com/blog/categories/poll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Poll: Ruby Problems for Beginners and Prizes</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/09/13/poll-ruby-problems-for-beginners-and-prizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/09/13/poll-ruby-problems-for-beginners-and-prizes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many RubyLearning participants wrote in asking RubyLearning to start a
weekly post containing a problem to be solved using Ruby. A problem will
be posted here every week / fortnight and anyone is free to offer their
solution (the solution should be clear-cut, follow Ruby conventions and
still be easy to understand) as a comment to the blog post. A small
panel will evaluate the solutions received and decide the best amongst
them all. The person with the best solution will be awarded a token
prize which could be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://peepcode.com/&#34;&gt;Peepcode&lt;/a&gt; or a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pragprog.com/screencasts&#34;&gt;Pragmatic&lt;/a&gt; screencast or something
equivalent. Maybe some sponsors could chip in with some prizes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/ruby_challenge3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RPCFN&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyLearning is open to this idea and will start the same provided there
is a good response to this. There’s a single question poll below which
please answer and what’s more important is to post your thoughts,
suggestions etc. as comments to this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do have the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubyquiz.com/&#34;&gt;Ruby Quiz&lt;/a&gt;, a weekly programming
challenge for Ruby programmers. What’s also needed is something for
programmers starting off with Ruby. Maybe RubyLearning could provide
this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We look forward to your response(s) and thoughts, suggestions (thoughts
on the nature of the Ruby problem to be asked, evaluation criteria etc.)
as comments below&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should we start a weekly Ruby programming challenge for beginners?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes (96%, 339 Votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No (4%, 14 Votes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total Voters: &lt;strong&gt;353&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/wp-content/plugins/wp-polls/images/loading.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Loading
...&#34; title=&#34;Loading ...&#34; /&gt;
 Loading
&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you for the over-whelming response to the poll. The
poll is now closed. As the poll results suggest, RubyLearning is going
ahead and starting off the “Ruby Programming Challenge For Newbies
(RPCFN)” from Friday, 25th Sept. 2009. We are also getting a very
positive response from many Ruby Gurus and Sponsors. Work on the
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/ruby-programming-challenge-faq/&#34;&gt;RPCFN
FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is
underway. In the meantime, we still look forward to your response(s) and
thoughts, suggestions (thoughts on the nature of the Ruby problem to be
asked, evaluation criteria etc.) as comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can you help RubyLearning with your suggestions?</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2008/11/15/can-you-help-rubylearning-with-your-suggestions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2008/11/15/can-you-help-rubylearning-with-your-suggestions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
    New Course Offerings
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;update&#34;&gt;
    We&amp;#8217;re rapidly expanding our course offerings here at RubyLearning, trying to keep up with the enormous and ever-growing interest in &lt;strong&gt;Ruby&lt;/strong&gt;. But we need your &lt;b&gt;YOUR&lt;/b&gt; help because, as you know, Ruby is a big subject, and we&amp;#8217;d like to be sure to focus in on the areas of most interest to &lt;b&gt;you&lt;/b&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;A Note regarding the courses mentioned in the poll below&lt;/strong&gt;:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Ruby Testing and TDD&lt;/strong&gt;: (starting from the concepts of testing in general, Test::Unit and other tools are discussed. RSpec is not discussed. Suited for people trying to code test code.)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Ruby GUI&lt;/strong&gt;: (GUI programming. Which library do you recommend &amp;#8211; Shoes, FXRuby?)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Ruby: Git and GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;: (A short course where you study Git and GitHub. Basic operations are discussed. Publishing a gem using GitHub.)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Ruby &amp; SQLite3 database&lt;/strong&gt;: (Learn SQLite3 using Ruby. Beneficial for those who already know another database and for those are relatively new to database itself.)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;JRuby&lt;/strong&gt;: This course is already available, but wanted to check whether you want it.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Merb&lt;/strong&gt;: This is becoming very popular in the community.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please take a moment to complete a brief poll about the new course offerings we&amp;#8217;re considering. &lt;strong&gt;Also, please post your suggestions as comments to this blog post&lt;/strong&gt;. It won&amp;#8217;t take more than a minute or two.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;h3&gt;
    THE POLL IS NOW CLOSED
  &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tag/Poll&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;Poll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tag/Ruby&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tag/Ruby+Courses&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;Ruby Courses&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tag/The+Ruby+Programming+Language&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;The Ruby Programming Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>