<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Promotions on RubyLearning Blog</title>
    <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/categories/book-promotions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Promotions on RubyLearning Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://rubylearning.com/blog/categories/book-promotions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2012/07/09/book-review-exploring-everyday-things-with-r-and-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2012/07/09/book-review-exploring-everyday-things-with-r-and-ruby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A book review of &lt;strong&gt;Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby&lt;/strong&gt;.
Review by: RubyLearning’s mentor Victor Goff.
Book author: Sau Sheong Chang.
Publisher: O’Reilly Media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/cat.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby&#34; /&gt;

I got the opportunity to review &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920022626.do&#34;&gt;Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby&lt;/a&gt;
by Sau Sheong Chang and published by O’Reilly Media.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:book&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:book&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book, as expected, talks about R and Ruby. The first chapters cover
 Ruby at an introductory level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first chapter, after showing how you can install Ruby and an
 introduction to the basics of Ruby, he also provides “a quick
 introduction to Shoes, a simple but powerful UI toolkit for
 Ruby”&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:shoes&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:shoes&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, with installation suggestions and sample code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His introduction to Ruby covers the basics and is just a bit more than
 enough to understand the code in the rest of his book. I think he did a
 really good job of that. The second part of the first chapter, covering
 Shoes, explains Shoes in a nutshell rather well, I think. You will get
 to use Shoes in later chapters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then goes on to introduce R, which I had not used before. He covers
 in a way that was fairly straightforward to install and get running.
 Within a few moments, I had R installed and the ‘normal’ graphical tools
 up and running and was able to run some sample code, and even had graphs
 floating around my screen based on data that I created from the samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after that, I had R code being created in my favorite text
 editor, and executing code right from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His introduction to the language is fairly quick, but again, just a bit
 more than enough to get you going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also covers some statistical transformation examples to change the
 statistical data into plottable information. That is a good thing,
 because throughout the book, you will be needing to recognize this in
 the examples, and will have fun producing your own graphical
 representations of data you get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all that is enough to get you started creating models to solve real
 world problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, do you need to convince your boss that you need more
 restrooms available for the people in your office? You can provide some
 simulations and reports and graphs (the boss likes graphs, right?) to
 support your argument, or will it support his assertion that what you
 have is just the right amount?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gets to the fun part. Have you ever wondered how to mine data from
 your own e-mail? To find trends of when you send mail, or who you
 communicate with most? Finding the most often used words and the
 trending themes in your communications? You are in luck. He will take
 you through the Enron Saga to lightly touch on analyzing that e-mail
 data&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:enron&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:enron&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but easily apply it to your own IMAP e-mail accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about biometrics, recording your own heartbeat through a home-made
 electronic stethoscope? Yes, you will be able to do this, and take
 measurements, and analyze them graphically. Combine that with pulse
 oximetry with your webcam and you might have just enough evidence to
 convince your boss that your cubicle is suffocating you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounds fun enough, but it will involve analyzing sound files and
 video files to get the readings and measurements that you want to
 produce in a graphical chart. That makes it fun to the nth power, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, what can be more fun than Boid’s… and boid &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; the
 woid&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:boids&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:boids&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in this next chapter. Using Ruby Shoes you will
 explore the flocking of birds, you will write a simulation and are
 encouraged to continue playing on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is an extension of the Boids and introduces the mortality
 and procreation of the boids, which were prior to this immortals in a
 veritable utopia. Life simulated and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I really enjoyed this book, it was easy to read, had some math
 in it, of course, but nothing that requires advanced math. And the
 topics were fun to work through. And there is plenty of room to
 experiment and explore after finishing the chapters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this review?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Book Review: Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby” –
 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Book+Review%3A+Exploring+Everyday+Things+with+R+and+Ruby+http%3A%2F%2Fbit.ly%2FNez21o&#34; title=&#34;Book Review: Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby&#34;&gt;Click to Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:book&#34;&gt;“Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby – O’Reilly Media.” 2012. &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920022626.do&#34;&gt;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920022626.do&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:book&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:shoes&#34;&gt;“Exploring Everyday Things with R and Ruby &amp;gt; 1. The Hat and the …” 2012. &lt;a href=&#34;http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/-/9781449342203/1dot-the-hat-and-the-whip/id2776202&#34;&gt;http://my.safaribooksonline.com/book/-/9781449342203/1dot-the-hat-and-the-whip/id2776202&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:shoes&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:enron&#34;&gt;“Enron Email Dataset.” 2004. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~enron/&#34;&gt;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~enron/&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:enron&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:boids&#34;&gt;Did you see what I did there? “The Trashman – The surfin bird – YouTube.” 2007. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QXLqMB6vBic&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QXLqMB6vBic&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:8e5e2b210ecb50fa990f38cc02eb76d8:boids&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloning Internet Applications with Ruby by Chang Sau Sheong</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2010/10/14/cloning-internet-applications-with-ruby-by-chang-sau-sheong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2010/10/14/cloning-internet-applications-with-ruby-by-chang-sau-sheong/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloning-internet-applications-with-ruby-by-chang-sau-sheong:2927053795d6e55f58007f13ce5f2ef4&#34;&gt;Cloning Internet Applications with Ruby by Chang Sau Sheong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.packtpub.com/cloning-internet-applications-with-ruby/book&#34;&gt;Cloning Internet Applications with
Ruby&lt;/a&gt;
is a new Ruby book by Chang Sau Sheong and published by Packt
Publishing. It’s now for sale at \$34.12 at Amazon. In India, it’s
available at a special price of Rs. 837.25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.packtpub.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/productview_ebook/1063OS_MockupCover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloning Internet Applications with
Ruby&#34; /&gt;

This book is for those interested in and with some experience with web
applications. The interesting thing is that the author describes four
well-known applications and shows you not only how to implement each
one, but describes different concerns about each type of application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author will walk you through the code, but will not teach you
in-depth programming theory, instead he will show you the parts that may
be used to put together clones of these four famous services. He will
also go over a quick history of each service type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you will not even get to page sixty, and you will have a
URL Shortening Clone built and deployed. He shows you the ‘parts’ that
you will use with Ruby to get it up and running. He walks you through
the installation of Sinatra, Haml, and DataMapper. And then shows you
how to use Blueprint CSS, Google Chart API, and HostIP. Alternatively,
he goes over quickly how to deploy using Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next application you will look at is TwitterClone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will use the following: JSON, GoogleClientLogin, Gravatar, and
TinyURL, RPX (authentication provisioning service), TinyURL, and of
course, Heroku for non-local deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the first clone, you will review why he chose Twitter (kind of
obvious, right?), how it is popular and valued, and some of the issues
faced. He will show you a data map of the features, and by page 120, you
have done it again, went from Design to Implementation, to Deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next exercise is cloning Flickr, and the author brings you the
history, and overview, and then goes through the steps with you once
again, to bring you to the last two chapters in the book, which clones
Facebook! And it really isn’t as complex as you may think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun with this book, it will give you some insights, and may help to
simplify a few tasks that you wanted to do, but were maybe intimidated
by. It turns out, it isn’t as complex as it may first appear!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you read this book? Why don’t you share your experiences with us?
Let us know in the comments section of this post. Thanks!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: The Joy of Clojure</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2010/05/08/book-promotion-the-joy-of-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2010/05/08/book-promotion-the-joy-of-clojure/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-promotion-the-joy-of-clojure:25485a31d404219193dcf4bd6386001b&#34;&gt;Book Promotion: The Joy of Clojure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/fogus/&#34;&gt;The
Joy of Clojure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” by author Michael
Fogus and Chris Houser. The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that
it gives the participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact
with the author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of
the book, all for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/fogus/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/fogusbook.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Joy of
Clojure&#34; title=&#34;The Joy of Clojure&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;25 to 27 May 2010&lt;/strong&gt;. Michael Fogus will be
online in the forum to answer your questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Clojure programming
can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
use Enrollment key: &lt;strong&gt;BPCE101&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start posting your questions related to the book,
immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it’s
free to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous book promotions were a big success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgements:25485a31d404219193dcf4bd6386001b&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2010/03/10/michael-fogus-talks-to-rubylearnings-clojure-course-participants/&#34;&gt;Michaelsmore.
Fogus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/fogus/&#34;&gt;Manning Publications Co.&lt;/a&gt; for
sponsoring three ebook winners (participants asking the best
questions) and for offering a 35% discount for any version of The
Joy of Clojure (print book+MEAP or ebook+MEAP) to the participants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book
promotion, contact: satish.talim [at] gmail [dot] com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Author Peter Cooper</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/08/20/interview-author-peter-cooper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/08/20/interview-author-peter-cooper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Book Promotion: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Beginning Ruby 2nd Edition&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; starts soon. Win
one of four books to be given out for active participation. The coolest
thing? Author &lt;strong&gt;Peter Cooper&lt;/strong&gt; will be on site to answer questions!
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/08/12/book-promotion-beginning-ruby-2nd-edition/&#34;&gt;Click
here&lt;/a&gt;
for more details. Here, in this brief interview, Satish Talim of
RubyLearning talks to Peter Cooper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.rubylearning.com/images/petercooper.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Peter
Cooper&#34; title=&#34;Peter Cooper&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Peter, could you tell us something about yourself &amp;ndash; your
background, where you are based?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m Peter Cooper, mostly known in the Ruby community for
running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rubyinside.com/&#34;&gt;Ruby Inside&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rubyflow.com/&#34;&gt;RubyFlow&lt;/a&gt;. I was also heavily involved with
the Rails community in 2005 and 2006 and released some of the first
tagging and AJAX stuff for Rails developers, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t been
particularly involved with the Rails community much since then. I&amp;rsquo;m also
the author of Beginning Ruby, the subject of this promo, have been an
advisor and contributor on a couple of other Ruby books (such as Ruby In
Practice and Design Patterns in Ruby).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in the north of England in a pretty remote area. On the plus
side, I have a great Internet connection, a cheap(ish) mortgage, and
lots of open space so in theory it should be perfect for someone in my
line of work! Since selling my startup, &lt;a href=&#34;http://feed.informer.com/&#34;&gt;Feed
Digest&lt;/a&gt;, back in 2007 I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to spend
more time working on &amp;ldquo;experiments&amp;rdquo; and what were previously side
projects, such as Ruby Inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/begrubyicon1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Beginning Ruby 2nd
Edition&#34; title=&#34;Beginning Ruby 2nd Edition&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What inspired/prompted you to write the book &amp;ldquo;Beginning
Ruby&amp;rdquo;? What need were you trying to fill?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I was routinely posting about Ruby on my personal blog
back in 2005 and an editor from Apress got in touch with me to throw
around ideas about writing their first Ruby book. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been keen
to write a beginners&amp;rsquo; book on some topic or another so it seemed like a
perfect opportunity to write a beginners&amp;rsquo; book to Ruby. I also felt that
Ruby didn&amp;rsquo;t have any good books dedicated to beginners. The Pickaxe, for
example, is an awesome reference book but I found it poor to learn Ruby
from from scratch. I wanted to see a book that was like the books I
learned C and BASIC from in the 1980s; that was the tradition I wanted
to follow in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Who&amp;rsquo;s the audience for your book &amp;ndash; Beginning Ruby?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t mean it to sound like a smartass answer but,
sincerely, beginners! More specifically, it tries to cover three types
of beginner &amp;ndash; people who are new to programming in general, existing
programmers with no OOP or dynamic language experience, and existing
programmers who understand object orientation and dynamic languages but
who don&amp;rsquo;t know Ruby yet. I&amp;rsquo;d say it aims more toward the first two
types, but Python or C# programmers, say, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel too slowed down
by my book as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to skip the introductions to concepts like
object orientation and relational databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The book is now into its second edition. What all has
changed from the 1st edition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; A lot more has changed in the world of Ruby than I
anticipated when taking on the second edition. There have been a lot of
URL and resource changes, as well as some natural library progressions,
such as covering Feedzirra instead of FeedTools. More significantly, the
chapter that was originally devoted to Rails now covers Rails, Sinatra,
and Ramaze, so that some balance is maintained since there are so many
webapp frameworks to choose from in Ruby nowadays. A chapter on GUI
programming (mostly based on Shoes) has been added as some people felt
this was a major area the original edition failed to cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What direction do you see Ruby taking in the years to
come?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I think we&amp;rsquo;re at a crucial point in Ruby&amp;rsquo;s life where a
year or two of inactivity and indifference could prompt the start of
Ruby&amp;rsquo;s decline. I&amp;rsquo;m doing my small part to prevent that from happening,
and hopefully the community and Ruby&amp;rsquo;s developers can keep up with the
exciting developments and game changing ideas to push things forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Interesting to note that you added a topic on Sinatra. In
a recent interview with RubyLearning.org, you mentioned that you would
be using Sinatra in more of your projects. Can you give us more details
on this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I first got into Sinatra late in 2008 when it was already
relatively mature and really enjoyed the small community that had built
up around it. It reminded me a lot of Rails in late 2004. In Sinatra&amp;rsquo;s
favor, though, was a severely reduced amount of &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; compared to
similar systems, and I loved the way you could write stuff in a very
&amp;ldquo;Rubyish&amp;rdquo; from-the-ground-up style. Rails isn&amp;rsquo;t totally flexible but its
opinions can get in the way if you disagree with them &amp;ndash; the gung-ho dive
into REST, for example, which I&amp;rsquo;m convinced will be poo-pooed in a
couple of years much as XHTML has been lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, recently I&amp;rsquo;ve become unconvinced of Sinatra&amp;rsquo;s abilities
to scale to large projects. It&amp;rsquo;s not its designated use case, and while
it&amp;rsquo;s possible, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d want to deal with the mess. Rails 3
still seems like vaporware to me but if it delivers on its main promises
of flexibility in terms of ORMs, JavaScript libraries, and so forth, I
could find myself strongly drawn back into the Rails fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you Peter. In case you have any queries and/or questions, kindly
post your questions here (as comments to this blog post) and Peter would
be glad to answer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: Beginning Ruby 2nd Edition</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/08/12/book-promotion-beginning-ruby-2nd-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/08/12/book-promotion-beginning-ruby-2nd-edition/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book
&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Beginning Ruby 2nd Edition&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by author Peter Cooper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apress.com/book/view/9781430223634&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/begrubyicon1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Beginning Ruby 2nd
Edition&#34; title=&#34;Beginning Ruby 2nd Edition&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-promotion-beginning-ruby-2nd-edition:d6d56cce3f4bdc3d40a0f06ad3f1863e&#34;&gt;Book Promotion: Beginning Ruby 2nd Edition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that it gives the
participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact with the
author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of the book,
all for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;25 to 27 August 2009&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Ruby programming
can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
use Enrollment key: &lt;strong&gt;BPCE101&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start posting your questions related to the book,
immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember:&lt;/strong&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it&amp;rsquo;s
free to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous book promotions of &amp;ldquo;Wicked Cool Ruby Scripts&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rails Test
Prescriptions&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ruby in Practice&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Head First Rails&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Programming
Ruby 1.9″, &amp;ldquo;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Foundation Rails 2″, &amp;ldquo;Ruby Best
Practices&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Ruby on Rails for Microsoft Developers&amp;rdquo; were a big
success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book
promotion, contact: mail [at] satishtalim [dot] com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: Ruby on Rails for Microsoft Developers</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/07/07/book-promotion-ruby-on-rails-for-microsoft-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/07/07/book-promotion-ruby-on-rails-for-microsoft-developers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-promotion-ruby-on-rails-for-microsoft-developers:d83d7e3cc3d51745a1df31484b64f7af&#34;&gt;Book Promotion: Ruby on Rails for Microsoft Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book “&lt;strong&gt;Ruby on
Rails for Microsoft Developers&lt;/strong&gt;” by author Antonio Cangiano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wrox.com/WileyCDA/WroxTitle/Ruby-on-Rails-for-Microsoft-Developers.productCd-0470374950.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/Ruby-on-Rail_square.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Ruby on Rails for Microsoft
Developers&#34; title=&#34;Ruby on Rails for Microsoft Developers&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that it gives the
participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact with the
author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of the book,
all for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;14 to 16 July 2009&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Ruby programming
can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
use Enrollment key: &lt;strong&gt;BPCE101&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start posting your questions related to the book,
immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it’s
free to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous book promotions of “Wicked Cool Ruby Scripts”, “Rails Test
Prescriptions”, “Ruby in Practice”, “Head First Rails”, “Programming
Ruby 1.9″, “The Well-Grounded Rubyist”, “Foundation Rails 2″ and “Ruby
Best Practices” were a big success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book
promotion, contact: mail [at] satishtalim [dot] com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Author Gregory Brown</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/21/interview-author-gregory-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/21/interview-author-gregory-brown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
    Our Book Promotion: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Ruby Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; starts soon. Win one of four books to be given out for active participation. The coolest thing? Author &lt;b&gt;Gregory Brown&lt;/b&gt; will be on site to answer questions! &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/20/book-promotion-ruby-best-practices/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more details. Here, in this brief interview, Satish Talim of RubyLearning talks to Gregory Brown.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;Gregory Brown&#34; src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/greg_brown.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gregory Brown&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Gregory, could you tell us something about yourself &amp;#8211; your background, where you are based?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Gregory&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;m a Ruby hacker that tends to spend a lot of time on free software. Right now, I&amp;#8217;m mainly working on two things: Working towards getting my pure Ruby PDF generation library Prawn to a 1.0 release, and starting up on a web based reporting system for RubySpec that I&amp;#8217;m calling Unity. Beyond that, I do most of my commercial work for a dev shop called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.madriska.com/&#34;&gt;Madriska Media Group&lt;/a&gt;, where I get to hack on hard and interesting problems with Brad Ediger. Though we are doing Rails work, you could hardly call it that, as many of our projects have some seriously hard CS problems in their critical path. But I like that stuff, so its a lot of fun!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    As for my background, I&amp;#8217;ve been programming since I was little, toying with various languages and systems that I could find. So I basically have my roots as a tinkerer, not a career programmer or academic. But things changed when I met James Edward Gray II over the net many years ago when I was writing some bad Perl code and releasing on Sourceforge. He helped show me how real programmers attack problems, helped turn my bad Perl code into good Perl code, and then later, when he moved into Ruby, helped me turned my bad Ruby code into good Ruby code. That helped me meet a lot of other really talented hackers, who I&amp;#8217;ve learned a lot from as well.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;Ruby Best Practices&#34; src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/rbp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ruby Best Practices&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What inspired/prompted you to write &amp;#8220;Ruby Best Practices?&amp;#8221; What need were you trying to fill?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Gregory&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve tried to teach a lot of people how to program over time. These days, I have a pretty high success rate, but it used to be a real struggle for me. In my experience, a lot of people reach the technically proficient stage with a language or technology, but never reach the point where they see the beauty or power behind truly elegant code. When the novelty of learning a new skill wears off, I&amp;#8217;ve seen folks either start to hate their work, or just drop out entirely. I wanted to fix that, and RBP was born as a result of this itch of mine.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    The book has a heavy focus on exploring real code, and isn&amp;#8217;t very preachy. This way, the reader can discover for themselves the merits of the practices and idioms it exposes. I think this is key. Some Ruby books let you phone it home and make for an easy skim. RBP is better as a doorstop if you don&amp;#8217;t want to crack open your editor and try some things out. At the same time, its not aimed at gurus only. I think different people will get different things out of it, and that&amp;#8217;s what I shot for.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Who’s the audience for your book &amp;#8211; Ruby Best Practices?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Gregory&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This book is for those who care about improving their craft. A raw beginner may not find it very approachable, but anyone who&amp;#8217;s done at least a small project in Ruby could probably learn a lot from it. A key thing for prospective readers to keep in mind is that it is *not* just an information dump. You should plan to read the whole thing, or at least read it by the chapter. Keep your brain engaged, and your development environment at the ready. For those who enjoy experimenting a bit and sharpening their code reading skills, the book will be enjoyable and helpful.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    My hopes is that a more advanced reader might find the book downright fun. There is some seriously cool code in here, from a number of very interesting Ruby projects.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What direction do you see Ruby taking in the years to come?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Gregory&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I really don&amp;#8217;t know. I&amp;#8217;m a poor fortune teller and I think there needs to be a closer look at where we are right now before we can talk much about the future.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    I recently did a &lt;a href=&#34;http://goruco2009.confreaks.com/30-may-2009-11-00-where-is-ruby-really-heading-gregory-brown.html&#34;&gt;talk on this&lt;/a&gt;, which might be an interesting watch for those curious what I think about the current state of Ruby.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    If we can get a good sense of how things stack up right now, we can focus more on the immediate issues than on the more glamorous, pie-in-the-sky problems. I think if we do that, things will be just fine.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I know that it is too early to say, but looking back are there some topics that you now wish should have been covered or dropped from the book?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Gregory&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; For a book that&amp;#8217;s a little over 300 pages, I wrote over 700 pages of content. I aggressively edited things down to make sure the book is lean and tight. I am pretty happy with the outcome.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    As far as topics I wish I covered, some were limited by Ruby 1.9&amp;#8217;s progress at the time of writing, and my deadline expired before I had a chance to fully give certain things the respect they deserve. This book would have been better with a chapter on YARV performance tuning, but the tools and common practices basically still aren&amp;#8217;t there for that. It would have been nice to add a chapter on higher level design, things like SOLID and Connascence and other hardcore topics like that. But maybe that would have bloated the book too much.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Luckily, we have the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.rubybestpractices.com/&#34;&gt;Ruby Best Practices blog&lt;/a&gt; now. We can cover other topics there as they come up, and RBP can stay small and focused. That seems like the best of both worlds.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Anything else you would like to add?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Gregory&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;d like to say thanks for inviting me here. I really look forward to questions and feedback from the folks who participate in this promo. It should be fun.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you Gregory. In case you have any queries and/or questions, kindly post your questions here (as comments to this blog post) and Gregory would be glad to answer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: Ruby Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/20/book-promotion-ruby-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/20/book-promotion-ruby-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
    Book Promotion: Ruby Best Practices
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Ruby Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; by author Gregory Brown.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://oreilly.com/catalog/9780596523008/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/rbp.jpg&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px none;&#34; alt=&#34;Ruby Best Practices&#34; title=&#34;Ruby Best Practices&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that it gives the participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact with the author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of the book, all for free!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Here are the details:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;30 June to 2 July 2009&lt;/strong&gt;.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Ruby programming can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and use Enrollment key: &lt;b&gt;BPCE101&lt;/b&gt;.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      You can start posting your questions related to the book, immediately.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFFCC;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Remember:&lt;/b&gt; Don&amp;#8217;t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it&amp;#8217;s free to join&lt;/span&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    The previous book promotions of &amp;#8220;Wicked Cool Ruby Scripts&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Rails Test Prescriptions&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Ruby in Practice&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Head First Rails&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Programming Ruby 1.9&amp;#8243;, &amp;#8220;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Foundation Rails 2&amp;#8243; were a big success.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book promotion, contact: mail [at] satishtalim [dot] com
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Author Eldon Alameda</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/15/interview-author-eldon-alameda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/15/interview-author-eldon-alameda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
    Our Book Promotion: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation Rails 2&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; starts soon. Win one of four books to be given out for active participation. The coolest thing? Author &lt;b&gt;Eldon Alameda&lt;/b&gt; will be on site to answer questions! &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/10/book-promotion-foundation-rails-2/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more details. Here, in this brief interview, Satish Talim of RubyLearning talks to Eldon Alameda.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;Eldon Alameda&#34; src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/ealameda.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Eldon Alameda&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Eldon, could you tell us something about yourself &amp;#8211; your background, where you are based?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Eldon&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;m originally from California, but have been residing in Kansas City for the last 11 years. I have a large number of years of experience working for a variety of companies such as IBM, Sprint, dot-com&amp;#8217;s, advertising agencies, and even a stint as the central region webmaster for the National Weather Service. Currently I&amp;#8217;m working as an architect and as the leader of the core product development team for a technology startup in the digital incentive arena. It&amp;#8217;s a really fun environment as we&amp;#8217;re working on a fairly large and complex code base that has some very strict performance requirements.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    I&amp;#8217;m also an ex-Marine, so I can tend to be a bit on the opinionated and gruff side &amp;#8211; especially when it comes to code quality. Perhaps paradoxically, I&amp;#8217;m also a big Disney fan who tries to take my family to Disney World once a year.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;Foundation Rails 2&#34; src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/medallion.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Foundation Rails 2&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; How is your book &amp;#8220;Foundation Rails 2&amp;#8243; different from the other Rails books?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Eldon&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; That&amp;#8217;s a good question. To be honest, I was fairly resistant when the publisher first contacted me to ask me to write this book. It felt like there was already a huge selection of books and resources for a beginner to use to learn Rails and I didn&amp;#8217;t feel like writing another book unless it added value. When I took the time to take a deeper look at the beginners books that were available at the time, however, it seemed to me that there were some important gaps in them.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    For one, many of the books seemed to rely too heavily on using scaffolding and plugins. While these tools certainly have their place, I&amp;#8217;ve been called far too many times to &amp;#8220;fix&amp;#8221; projects where it was obvious that the original developer was over-using these tools and didn&amp;#8217;t understand the underlying code that these tools were adding to the project. For my book &amp;#8211; I really wanted to make sure that the reader had a solid understanding of the basics before I introduced these tools. Thus, I didn&amp;#8217;t cover scaffolding or plugins until chapter 9 and even then I present them only as a way to expedite the development of a prototype.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Secondly, it felt that many of the books out there had the goal of teaching Rails while building a single application in the book. While this sounds like a good idea, in practice, it felt like most of the books that chose this path were rushing the reader through the learning process in order to build the app. As Rails is composed of several individual libraries that work together, I opted to take the readers through a deeper hands-on tour of how to use each of the Rails libraries that provide its MVC architecture before bringing it all back together to build a sample application.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Finally, I really wanted to encourage readers to have fun and explore concepts beyond the simple examples that I provide in the book, so I really strived to give the reader something to play with in each chapter. So for most of the chapters I either was guiding the reader through experiments in the console or I was having them complete sample Rails applications using the tools that we were discussing in that chapter. I know that I feel that I learn best when I&amp;#8217;m getting my hands dirty in the code and so I was hoping that by ensuring that readers were able to be actively playing with Rails code throughout the book, that they would be able to learn better as well.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Who’s the audience for your book &amp;#8211; Foundation Rails 2?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Eldon&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I wrote this book with goal of providing a solid introduction to Rails for people who have some passing familiarity with other scripting languages such as JavaScript or PHP. That being said, my main requirement for readers of my book is simply a motivation to learn and curiosity to play around with the code beyond just the words on the page. I don&amp;#8217;t believe it&amp;#8217;s possible to learn how to code anything without actually investing the time at the keyboard yourself.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Looking back are there some topics that you now wish should have been covered or dropped from the book?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Eldon&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately, I&amp;#8217;m somewhat of a perfectionist so if given more time to write the book I would have loved to continue refining and expanding many of the areas of the book. Most notably, while I was able to provide an introduction to testing using Rspec, I would have loved to have expanded that and given readers even more value.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Secondly, as someone who now has to interview and hire other Rails developers &amp;#8211; &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFFCC;&#34;&gt;one of my big frustrations is how many &amp;#8220;professional&amp;#8221; Rails developers I meet who have a very shallow knowledge of core Ruby or even generic object-oriented design concepts&lt;/span&gt;. So those are areas that I would have loved to expand upon in my book if I could have done it without overwhelming the reader.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Anything else you would like to add?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Eldon&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The best advice I can give is one of my core personal philosophies and something that I try to communicate to my team members; which is the importance of what I call the &amp;#8220;Sharpening the Axe&amp;#8221;. That term is based on a bible verse I once had to memorize when I was younger which stated that:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      &amp;#8220;If the axe is blunt, and one doesn&amp;#8217;t sharpen the edge, then he must use more strength; but skill brings success.&amp;#8221;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    The basic premise being that you need to continually be looking to keep yourself and your skills sharp. The stronger your foundation is on the basics, then the easier it will be for you to solve the bigger problems. Conversely if you&amp;#8217;re weak on the fundamentals, then you can still solve problem but they&amp;#8217;re going to difficult and consume more of your energy.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    So if you find that you don&amp;#8217;t feel like you quite understand how something like blocks work in Ruby, you should take the time out of your schedule to invest in digging deeper into that area until you truly learn it. The quality of resources for learning Ruby that are available today are light-years ahead of what what was available when I first started coding in Ruby.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you Eldon. In case you have any queries and/or questions, kindly post your questions here (as comments to this blog post) and Eldon would be glad to answer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: Foundation Rails 2</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/10/book-promotion-foundation-rails-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/10/book-promotion-foundation-rails-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
    Book Promotion: Foundation Rails 2
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation Rails 2&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; by author Eldon Alameda.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.friendsofed.com/book.html?isbn=9781430210399&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/medallion.jpg&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px none;&#34; alt=&#34;Foundation Rails 2&#34; title=&#34;Foundation Rails 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that it gives the participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact with the author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of the book, all for free!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Here are the details:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;16th to 18th June 2009&lt;/strong&gt;.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Ruby programming can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and use Enrollment key: &lt;b&gt;BPCE101&lt;/b&gt;.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      You can start posting your questions related to the book, immediately.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFFCC;&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Remember:&lt;/b&gt; Don&amp;#8217;t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it&amp;#8217;s free to join&lt;/span&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    The previous book promotions of &amp;#8220;Wicked Cool Ruby Scripts&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Rails Test Prescriptions&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Ruby in Practice&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Head First Rails&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Programming Ruby 1.9&amp;#8243; were a big success.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book promotion, contact: mail [at] satishtalim [dot] com
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Author David Black</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/09/interview-author-david-black/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/06/09/interview-author-david-black/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
    Our Book Promotion: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; starts today. Win one of four books to be given out for active participation. The coolest thing? Author &lt;b&gt;David A. Black&lt;/b&gt; will be on site to answer questions! &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/29/book-promotion-the-well-grounded-rubyist/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more details. Here, in this brief interview, Satish Talim of RubyLearning talks to David A. Black.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;David A. Black. Photo credit: James Duncan Davidson&#34; src=&#34;http://www.rubylearning.com/images/david.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David A. Black&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; David, could you tell us something about yourself &amp;#8211; your background, where you are based?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;David&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;m from Connecticut originally, and I live in New Jersey. My first computer programming experiences were with a PDP-8 and PDP-10, in the early 1970s. I was thirteen years old, and in those days, unlike today, a thirteen-year-old programmer was a rarity! I didn&amp;#8217;t do much with computers in later years until the late 1980s, when I got my first PC and gravitated to programming again. Meanwhile, I was starting an academic career in a different field, and taught college from 1992 to 2005. I then made the decision to leave the university and devote myself full-time to Ruby and Rails development, training, and writing.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; title=&#34;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&#34; src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/twgrcover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Who&amp;#8217;s the audience for your book &amp;#8211; The Well-Grounded Rubyist? Does it teach Ruby programming or is it a reference book?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;David&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The Well-Grounded Rubyist is for programmers who are new to Ruby, as well as people who have done some work with Ruby and now want to learn it more deeply and systematically. It&amp;#8217;s definitely a teaching book rather than a Ruby reference work &amp;#8212; not that it doesn&amp;#8217;t cover lots of language features and techniques, but its purpose is to bring you to a deep understanding of how things work in Ruby, and to give you the foundation you need for a long-term, ongoing relationship with the language.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    I think of myself as having switched careers from teacher to computer programmer, but at the same time, there&amp;#8217;s definitely a teacher part of me that&amp;#8217;s always there. I love explaining things to people and helping them &amp;#8220;get it&amp;#8221;, and writing a book like this is the perfect way to combine my programmer and teacher sides. That&amp;#8217;s also why I do a lot of Ruby and Rails training, and why I truly enjoy it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; How different is this book from your other book &amp;#8211; &amp;#8220;Ruby for Rails&amp;#8221;?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;David&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; TWGR is what I have described as a &amp;#8220;repurposing&amp;#8221; of R4R. Of course the main difference is that TWGR doesn&amp;#8217;t talk about Rails. But it also covers a lot more of Ruby, and brings it up to date by focusing on Ruby 1.9.1.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    In working on TWGR I&amp;#8217;ve drawn on material from R4R, but everything has been revisited, revised, and updated. There was no automatic cut-and-paste from R4R. It was important to me for TWGR to stand entirely on its own &amp;#8212; and the fact that it&amp;#8217;s about a different version of Ruby, as well as being more inclusive, reinforced that need.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    In fact, when I started working on TWGR I thought it would be easier than it turned out to be. Just take out Rails, add some new material, update everything, and there it is! It turned out to be much harder than that, and it took longer than I expected. But that turned out to be a blessing in disguise, since the book&amp;#8217;s appearance has coincided nicely with Ruby 1.9.1, the first stable version of Ruby 1.9.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I know that it is too early to say, but looking back are there some topics that you now wish should have been covered or dropped from the book?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;David&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing so far, though as you say it&amp;#8217;s still early &lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; /&gt; There&amp;#8217;s always judgment involved in choosing topics and deciding what to emphasize. My guiding principle has been to try to leave the reader in a position where, even though there&amp;#8217;s more to learn, there won&amp;#8217;t be any big surprises: everything you learn about Ruby later on will relate in some way to what you&amp;#8217;ve learned in the book.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Anything else you would like to add?&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;David&gt;&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Only to thank you for inviting me to talk about the book, and that I hope everyone learns from it and enjoys it!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#CC3333;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you David. In case you have any queries and/or questions, kindly post your questions here (as comments to this blog post) and David would be glad to answer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: The Well-Grounded Rubyist</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/29/book-promotion-the-well-grounded-rubyist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/29/book-promotion-the-well-grounded-rubyist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book “&lt;strong&gt;The
Well-Grounded Rubyist&lt;/strong&gt;” by author David Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manning.com/black2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/twgrcover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&#34; title=&#34;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that it gives the
participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact with the
author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of the book,
all for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;9th to 11th June 2009&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Ruby programming
can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
use Enrollment key: &lt;strong&gt;BPCE101&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start posting your questions related to the book,
immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it’s
free to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous book promotions of “Wicked Cool Ruby Scripts”, “Rails Test
Prescriptions”, “Ruby in Practice” and “Head First Rails” were a big
success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book
promotion, contact: mail [at] satishtalim [dot] com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: Programming Ruby 1.9</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/24/book-promotion-programming-ruby-1.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/24/book-promotion-programming-ruby-1.9/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-promotion-programming-ruby-1-9:a6a5dfbd0ffc7e4179b538cd4c94c1a9&#34;&gt;Book Promotion: Programming Ruby 1.9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book
“&lt;strong&gt;Programming Ruby 1.9&lt;/strong&gt;” by author Dave Thomas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pragprog.com/titles/ruby3/programming-ruby-1-9&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/ruby3_180.png&#34; alt=&#34;Programming Ruby
1.9&#34; title=&#34;Programming Ruby 1.9&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that it gives the
participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact with the
author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of the book;
all for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;2nd to 4th June 2009&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Ruby programming
can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
use Enrollment key: &lt;strong&gt;BPCE101&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start posting your questions related to the book,
immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message from Dave Thomas&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Although I know this is supposed to
be a book promotion, I’d like to take to opportunity here to talk
about Ruby, too. I love the language, and after more than 10 years
still find new things that surprise and delight me. I’d love to talk
with your members about those thingsâ€”about the importance of
loving and respecting the tools that you use. I’d love to talk about
Ruby 1.9, and about all the various issues that surround the
language. Let’s make programming fun again!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it’s
free to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous book promotions of “Wicked Cool Ruby Scripts”, “Rails Test
Prescriptions” and “Ruby in Practice” were a big success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book
promotion, contact: mail [at] satishtalim [dot] com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Author Dave Thomas</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/24/interview-author-dave-thomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/24/interview-author-dave-thomas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Book Promotion: “&lt;strong&gt;Programming Ruby 1.9&lt;/strong&gt;” starts soon. Win one of
four books to be given out for active participation. The coolest thing?
Author &lt;strong&gt;Dave Thomas&lt;/strong&gt; will be on site to answer questions! &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/24/book-promotion-programming-ruby-19/&#34;&gt;Click
here&lt;/a&gt;
for more details. Here, in this brief interview, Satish Talim of
RubyLearning talks to Dave Thomas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.pragprog.com/images/people/dave-large.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dave
Thomas&#34; title=&#34;Dave Thomas&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Dave, could you tell us something about yourself – your
background, where you are based?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Well, I was born in Cheshire, England (up by Liverpool). My
family moved around when I was young, living in Canada and the US,
before moving back to England in time for my secondary schooling. Back
then, we took a group of exams when you were &lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt; (the O-levels) and
another set at 18 (A-levels). A bunch of us took O-levels early, and the
school was looking for something that would keep us busy. The local
technical college had just started an A-level course in computers, so
some of us wandered across the road and started taking it. I fell in
love in the first week. We were creating Basic programs on paper tape
using an ASR-33 teletype, then sending them over a 110 baud modem to our
local town council’s ICL mainframe. And it was great! Somewhere in the
middle of that year I wrote what it possibly the world’s only
self-modifying Basic programâ€”we were only allowed to store 5 programs
up on the mainframe, so I wrote a program that stored other programs
inside itself, and that would extract and run those programs on demand.
The following summer I got a job writing code for a local water board,
and I decided to change my college applications from mathematics to
computer science. I ended up at Imperial College in London, which had an
incredibly good courseâ€”I enjoyed every minute (apart, perhaps, from
the statistics… :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating I worked for a small start-up. Initially the work was
in the UK, but pretty soon I was traveling around the world. The work
was great fun: we were doing all the weird interfacing between large
systems and different kinds of front ends (including some early
precursors to web browsers). I also worked for a small UK computer
manufacturer in their skunk works. Probably the most interesting project
there was the low-level interfaces to the hardware that did the checkout
of the Giotto satellite that went to Comet Halley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met my wife on a project in New York. After we married, she moved back
to the UK with me, but after our first boy was born we moved over to
Dallas, Texas, where I’ve now been living for 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy Hunt and I met on a project in the mid 90s, and we’ve been working
together ever since. We wrote &lt;em&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer&lt;/em&gt;, and formed a
business of the same name. A few years later, we used the experience we
gained on the production side of that book to form our own publishing
business. That business has grown and grown, and now takes the majority
of our time. But, I still carve out time to play with softwareâ€”that’s
still my passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/ruby3_180.png&#34; alt=&#34;Programming Ruby
1.9&#34; title=&#34;Programming Ruby 1.9&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Who’s the audience for your book – Programming Ruby 1.9?
Does it teach Ruby programming or is it a reference book?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I first came across Ruby about 10 years ago. At that time,
almost no one outside Japan had heard of it. Andy and I both wanted to
use Ruby in a book project we were considering, but discovered that the
explanations of Ruby were getting in the way of the material that was
supposed to be the topic of the book. So we put the original book
project on hold, and instead started writing up notes on Ruby. We wrote
those notes for developers who knew a programming language and who
wanted to get good at Ruby. And we wrote the book we’d want to read
ourselves: a fairly fast tutorial that skims through the main features,
starting not at the bottom (variables and if statements) but instead at
the top (classes and objects). After this, there’s a section on the
environment in which Ruby programs run: basically describing how to use
Ruby in the real world. We then documented all the built-in classes and
methods that come with Ruby. So it’s really three books in one. Anyone
who has programmed should find it an easy and instructive read. It both
teaches Ruby and is a reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What all has changed from the first edition of the book?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Oh, a lot! The most obvious changes have been driven by
Ruby itself. Ruby 1.9 has a ton of exciting new features. It’s
multinationalisation support is unprecedented. It now has a far more
functional feel. And a whole lot more classes and methods are now built
in. I haven’t counted, but I’d guess the number of built-in methods has
doubled since that first edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, much has changed in the Ruby community since that
first edition. When the first edition came out, almost no one was using
Ruby, so we didn’t really know good ways to do things. Now we know a lot
more, and I’ve tried to incorporate all that experience that we’ve
gained into the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ve taken literally thousands of pieces of individual feedback
and used them to change the way I describe things. The tutorial in
particular has changed a lot, and now contains many more self-contained
example programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very proud of this resultâ€”the book is both an evolution of the
previous two books, but it’s also a fairly dramatic rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, just to clarify, &lt;em&gt;Programming Ruby 1.9&lt;/em&gt; is technically not a new
edition of the previous book. We originally planned it to be, as we
anticipated that Ruby 1.9 would replace Ruby 1.8. But the reality is
that many people are still using 1.8, so we wanted to keep the second
edition of the PickAxe (which covers 1.8) around as well. Booksellers
automatically pull a prior edition out of stock if you release a new
one, and we didn’t want that to happen, so &lt;em&gt;Programming Ruby 1.9&lt;/em&gt; is
technically a brand new book, rather than being a new edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Tell us something about “The Pragmatic Bookshelf”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Andy and I wrote both &lt;em&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer&lt;/em&gt; and the
first edition of &lt;em&gt;Programming Ruby&lt;/em&gt; for Addison Wesley. But, unlike most
authors, we did all the typesetting, layout, indexing, and so on,
ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote most of the book production system for this exercise. I wanted
to avoid that kinds of problems most technical book authors face. I
wanted to keep my source code in real program files, where it could be
run and tested, rather that cut-and-paste it into the book. I wanted to
use plain text to store the book’s content, because then we could use
programmer’s tools, such as source code control, &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt;. And
I wanted the books to look nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the Ruby book, we got back to our consulting business.
And we noticed that many of the teams we were working with didn’t use
basic practicesâ€”things such as unit testing, source code control, and
automationâ€”that we considered essential to successfully completing
software projects. So we decided to start writing a set of three books
on these areas. We were going to write them with Addison Wesley, but we
got to thinking: we already had the technology to create the books: all
we’d need is access to a book printer and a way of distributing the
result. How hard could that be? Well, that’s what we did. And we’re
still discovering just how hard the rest is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’ve had a blast. The Pragmatic Bookshelf isn’t like other
publishers. For a start, we’re a publisher for developers. We use
developer tools to get books created. When you sign up as an author, we
create a Subversion repository where you write your book. You don’t use
something like Word to author your text. Instead you write directly in
the markup language that we use to create the final typeset product.
This means that you’re always working with what will become the final
bookâ€”we don’t take what you type and then get someone else to typeset
it using a different tool. This immediacy means we can get a book into
print faster that just about anyone else. If you want, you can build
that final version on your machine, just as we do when we send a book to
the printer. Or you can let our continuous build system do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also automate just about everything we can. For example, if an author
has an updated version of a book that they’d like to push out to their
readers, I can issue a single &lt;code&gt;rake&lt;/code&gt; command (&lt;code&gt;rake&lt;/code&gt; is a build tool
written in Ruby) will create up-to-date PDF, mobi, and epub versions of
the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heavy use of tools and automation means that our overhead is really
low. And that in turn means we can pay our authors well: we pay 3 to 4
times more as a royalty than other publishers we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also helps that we really aren’t publishers, so we don’t know how
things are supposed to be done. I think we were the first people to
offer PDF versions of all our titles. (We now offer epub and mobi
versions too, for use on eBook devices and mobile phones). We were the
first publisher to have a solid beta-book program, where we give readers
early access to books as they are in development. I think we were the
first publisher to create electronic versions of our books with no DRM,
instead adding a simply watermark to the books and relying on our
customers’ honesty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my personal perspective, it’s a very heady business: I get to help
select books that we publish based on books that I’d personally like to
read. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I know that it is too early to say, but looking back are
there some topics that you now wish should have been covered or dropped
from the book?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Not really: I only just finished the book, and I made all
the changes I wanted to make while I was rewriting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every now and then I think that maybe I should split it into two books,
but I still think it’s valuable to have all the content in one place.
Having it in one volume also makes it cheaper for its readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Anything else you would like to add?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Although I know this is supposed to be a book promotion,
I’d like to take to opportunity here to talk about Ruby, too. I love the
language, and after more than 10 years still find new things that
surprise and delight me. I’d love to talk with your members about those
thingsâ€”about the importance of loving and respecting the tools that
you use. I’d love to talk about Ruby 1.9, and about all the various
issues that surround the language. Let’s make programming fun again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you Dave. In case you have any queries and/or questions, kindly
post your questions here (as comments to this blog post) and Dave would
be glad to answer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Promotion: Head First Rails</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/20/book-promotion-head-first-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/05/20/book-promotion-head-first-rails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RubyLearning is pleased to announce the promotion of the book “&lt;strong&gt;Head
First Rails&lt;/strong&gt;” by author David Griffiths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://oreilly.com/catalog/9780596515775/?CMP=ILC-hf1st#top&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/hfrails_180x180.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Head First
Rails&#34; title=&#34;Head First Rails&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general idea of a &lt;strong&gt;book promotion&lt;/strong&gt; is that it gives the
participants a chance to ask relevant questions, interact with the
author of the book and in the process possibly win a copy of the book;
all for free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promotion Period: &lt;strong&gt;26th to 28th May 2009&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;35% discount on the book offered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registrations have started. Anyone interested in Ruby programming
can join. It is &lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt;. Join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/class/course/view.php?id=35&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
use Enrollment key: &lt;strong&gt;BPCE101&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can start posting your questions related to the book,
immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait! You could win a copy of this book and it’s
free to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous book promotions of “Wicked Cool Ruby Scripts” and “Rails
Test Prescriptions” were a big success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions related to this blog post or to schedule a new book
promotion, contact: mail [at] satishtalim [dot] com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>