<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Merb on RubyLearning Blog</title>
    <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/categories/merb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Merb on RubyLearning Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://rubylearning.com/blog/categories/merb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>SapnaSolutions Transforming Pune City into a Rails Hub</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/04/09/sapnasolutions-transforming-pune-city-into-a-rails-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/04/09/sapnasolutions-transforming-pune-city-into-a-rails-hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Adams&lt;/strong&gt; is the CTO and Co-Founder of &lt;strong&gt;SapnaSolutions&lt;/strong&gt;.
SapnaSolutions is on a mission of transforming Pune city into a Ruby on
Rails hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.rubylearning.com/images/NickAdams.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nick
Adams&#34; title=&#34;Nick Adams&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish Talim&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Nick, could you tell us something about yourself –
your background, where you are based?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Adams&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I came to India in early 2008 to seek my fortunes
with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.entrip.com/&#34;&gt;EnTrip&lt;/a&gt;, our web based travel portal. My
friend Anthony and I decided to do something doubly different and start
a company in another country rather than work in London after we
graduated. We joined forces with Yann, a French entrepreneur with
experience at StudiVZ, to create
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sapnasolutions.com/en&#34;&gt;SapnaSolutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; earlier this year
here in Pune, India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/SapnaSolutions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SapnaSolutions&#34; title=&#34;SapnaSolutions&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Could you tell us a little more about SapnaSolutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; SapnaSolutions is a new kind of development company.
Although we will use our European links to take outsourced work, we also
have a number of product and marketable web 2.0 ideas which we plan to
implement alongside our client work. Those products, one of which we are
working on at the moment, we hope to scale, and build the company
eventually into a Web 2.0 hot house. It makes the company atmosphere
electric, more like one of a start-up, than an ordinary development
company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Nick, why did you choose Ruby on Rails (RoR) as a
framework for development work at SapnaSolutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I have been working in Rails since early 2007 when I used
it to create the first prototype of ‘Trip’, which would later turn into
EnTrip. Ever since then, I’ve watched RoR and the community and the buzz
surrounding it grow and mature, and since most of the scalability issues
have been resolved, there seems no better framework on which to build a
new forward thinking web company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Were there any surprises in working with RoR?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Many, mostly pleasant! I remember when I was learning Ruby
and Rails, I continuously found myself surprised by how much ‘just
worked’. It’s mostly down to the elegance and power of Ruby, of course,
which is how most of the Rails magic is possible. One thing that’s
slightly surprising now is that Merb, a powerful and yet tight framework
is merging with the full and often thought of as bloated Rails 2.2
stack. I am very interested to see what will emerge and how easy
migration will be; hopefully that will be yet another pleasant surprise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What is your impression about the RoR scene in India and
especially in Pune, where your development center is based?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; When we started recruiting it was tough but once we got our
HR machine going we found that there are quite a number of RoR
developers available for hire in India. Unfortunately, the web geek
nature that is found in the active community surrounding Rails, is not
here yet. In India software is still seen largely as a tool, either for
a better paid job or for doing the bidding of a project manager. We are
yet to see the real interest in the web and in contributing to
technology that is needed in order for India to fully utilise the power
of it’s thousands of web developers. Here in Pune we are lucky to have
India’s first Ruby university course, and a number of companies using
RoR. A number of our developers have joined us from Pune, I think we are
set to have the city emerge as a strong contender to lead a new
generation of web savvy developers in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What advice would you give startups about platform
choices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What do you know? Choose something you are comfortable
with. A strong link between business and tech is important, so you can
assess quickly what is possible, how long it will take, and what the
cost will be. Knowing the technology you work with is a real benefit.
What is free? I would advise any startup to go open source, because it’s
free and because the communities in open source technologies are very
strong. What is fast? Choose the platforms that let you get your ideas
out there quickly, so the time to market and time to feedback is faster.
I would give a big thumbs up for Rails in this category – once you know
it, even challenging web apps are a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Getting back to SapnaSolutions, what are your future
plans?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; We intend to get going with client projects, and eventually
scale our products. We believe we are at a unique advantage by being
able to speak five different European languages in house, which allow us
to take projects from clients typically outside the Indian market, and
also build applications and products for emerging markets in Europe. My
own dream is to take EnTrip, my own startup forward, after a short lull
in development, which we expect to be possible as soon as we are up and
running with Sapna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Anything else you would like to add?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, thanks for everything you’re doing for the Ruby
community here in Pune Satish! The next challenge is engaging people
with it’s many applications, the Web being a very exciting such
application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you Nick. In case you have any queries and/or questions, kindly
post your questions here (as comments to this blog post) and Nick would
be glad to answer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Adam Wiggins on Heroku</title>
      <link>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/03/13/interview-adam-wiggins-on-heroku/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/03/13/interview-adam-wiggins-on-heroku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the eve of the first ever online “&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Sinatra&lt;/strong&gt;”
course, Satish Talim and Victor H. Goff III of RubyLearning caught up
with &lt;strong&gt;Adam Wiggins&lt;/strong&gt; and talked to him on &lt;strong&gt;Heroku&lt;/strong&gt; (pronounced
her-OH-koo), in this interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/AdamWiggins.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Adam Wiggins,
USA&#34; title=&#34;Adam Wiggins, USA&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish Talim&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Welcome, Adam and thanks for taking out time to
share your thoughts. For the benefit of the readers, could you tell us
something about your self?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam Wiggins&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; By day, I’m a Rubyist and entrepeneur. By night, I
evangelize critical thinking and skepticism, pontificate about economics
and cognition, and hack on music software and video games. Some people
have said that I’m a nice guy, but I vehemently deny such a vicious
rumor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blog at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://adam.blog.heroku.com/&#34;&gt;http://adam.blog.heroku.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heroku – It’s fast, it’s easy, and it just works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What’s Heroku and how did you get involved with it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I co-founded Heroku along with my partners Orion and James
in autumn 2007. Our elevator pitch is “instant Ruby deployment.” Heroku
is the fastest and simplest way to get a Rails, Merb, or Sinatra app
into production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; For a person new to development using Rack and Rack-based
web frameworks (like Sinatra, Merb, Ramaze, and Camping), how can Heroku
help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Passenger has done a lot for standardizing and simplifying
the deployment of Rack apps, but it’s still up to you to provision your
own server. Since basic Heroku apps are free, there’s nothing to stop
anyone with basic proficiency in Ruby and Git from getting their app
online instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;http://heroku.com/docs#toc25&#34;&gt;tutorial on deploying a Rack
app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victor&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; What is the long term goal of Heroku?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I like to think that we’re championing a revolution in app
deployment, similar to the agile revolution that happened in app
development over the past decade. Our vision is for deploying apps into
production to be as easy, fast, and fun as building apps with Rails or
the other great Ruby frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victor&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; When are you going to be ready for Prices and Options for
Heroku?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Pricing is already in beta. We don’t publish dates, but we
should have something for public consumption soon. If you’d like to
participate in the pricing beta, contact us:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://heroku.com/about&#34;&gt;http://heroku.com/about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victor&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I understand that Heroku can be used with Git, but does
that mean I have to leave my other versioning tools behind, or does it
play well with others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Git can live alongside Subversion or other version-control
tools. In fact, using them in tandem is a pretty good way to ease into
learning Git. You can also use Git purely as a deployment mechanism, as
described &lt;a href=&#34;http://heroku.com/docs#toc18&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/images/heroku-optimized.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Heroku
Logo&#34; title=&#34;Heroku&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victor&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Where can I find out where you are going to be speaking
and when?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Last year I spoke at Railsconf and Rubyconf, among others.
This year I’ll be doing a talk about Rack, Sinatra, and Rails Metal at
Railsconf, and participating in a panel with a bunch of great folks
including the authors of Rack and Thin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always find out what events I and the other cool dudes here at
Heroku are attending, on the sidebar to our
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.heroku.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satish &amp;amp; Victor&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks Adam for sharing your views with the
&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Sinatra&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3325873d2bd52b46279601788801d882:fn-1570-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3325873d2bd52b46279601788801d882:fn-1570-1&#34;&gt;0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;^&lt;/strong&gt; ” and ” &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to
Merb&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3325873d2bd52b46279601788801d882:fn-1570-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3325873d2bd52b46279601788801d882:fn-1570-2&#34;&gt;0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;^&lt;/strong&gt; ” course participants. You can connect with Adam
on twitter &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hirodusk&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;\
&lt;em&gt;The opinions expressed are those of Adam Wiggins and do not necessarily
reflect those of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.org/&#34;&gt;RubyLearning.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Sinatra&lt;/strong&gt;: Here are the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/02/25/introduction-to-sinatra-a-new-course/&#34;&gt;course
details&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref-1570-1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Merb&lt;/strong&gt;: Here are the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubylearning.com/blog/2009/03/02/introduction-to-merb-3rd-batch/&#34;&gt;course
details&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref-1570-2&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>